Finding Aid for Roger C. Storms Papers, 1960-1979
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Roger C. Storms Papers 1960-1979
Storms, Roger C. (Roger Clair), 1939-
3 linear ft.
85443 Aa 2
Prohibition activist and historian; correspondence and other materials relating to his work with various prohibition organizations and associated issues.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Roger C. Storms (donor no. 5179 ) and came to the library in multiple accessions.
The collection is open to research.
Roger C. Storms was born in Houlton, Maine, August 1939. He graduated from Eastern Baptist College in St. Davids, Pennsylvania in 1961 and from the University of Maine at Orono with a MA degree in 1968. For much of his career, he taught social studies in various schools and academies in Maine and Colorado. A life-long advocate of prohibition, Storms was active in the Prohibition National Committee, serving as secretary from 1969 until his death in 1980. He was also founder and president of the Partisan Prohibition Historical Society, 1969-1980. In addition, he served as vice president of the National Civic League and the National Prohibition Foundation and was on the state boards of the Colorado Right to Life Committee and the Colorado Alcohol Drug Education organization. He died in 1980 some months following an automobile accident.
The collection is arranged into the following series: Temperance and Prohibition papers; Partisan Prohibition Historical Society; Maine Prohibition Party; Other Organizational Files; and Miscellaneous and personal.
Subjects:
Partisan Prohibition Historical Society.; Prohibition--United States.; Prohibition Party (U.S.); Prohibition National Committee (U.S.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Partisan Prohibition Historical Society.; Storms, Roger C. (Roger Clair), 1939-
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Temperance and Prohibition papers
  The Temperance and Prohibition, 1960-1979 series consists mainly of files relating to Storms' work with the Prohibition National Committee, in particular from his years as secretary, 1969-1979.
  - 1960-February 1977, 37 folders (Box 1)
  - March 1977-December 1979, 15 folders (Box 2)
- Partisan Prohibition Historical Society
  - May 1971-1979, 22 folders (Box 2)
  - Response to Partisan Prohibition Historical Society Questionnaire (Box 2)
- Maine Prohibition Party
  - Correspondence December 1963-1971, 6 folders (Box 2)
- Other Organizational Files
  - "Christian Challenge" National Christian Citizen Committee, 1962-1964 (Box 3)
  - Christian Civic League of Maine, 1963-1967 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence (miscellaneous state), November 1969-November 1970 (Box 3)
  - Hoosier Challenge, 1962-1964 (Box 3)
  - National Civic League, May 1975-February 1978 (Box 3)
  - "New England Statesmen", Correspondence, 1962-January 1963, 1978 (Box 3)
  - National Right to Work Committee/Concerned Educators Against Forced Unionism, June 1975-April 1978 (Box 3)
  - National Temperance and Prohibition Council 1969, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Pennsylvania Prohibition Committee, 1964-1968 (Box 3)
  - Prohibition National Committee budgets, 1975-1978 (Box 3)
  - Prohibition National Convention, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Prohibition Party, Presidential campaign, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Prohibition Trust Fund Association, 1978 (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous and personal
  - Biographical material (Box 3)
  - Historical research (Box 3)
  - Research materials (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous materials, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Addresses (Box 3)
  - Writings, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Letters to the Public (Box 3)
  - Letters to the Editor (Box 3)
  - Printed materials (Box 3)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1974-1978 (Box 3)
  - Prohibition History Notes, 1971-1976 (incomplete set) (Box 3)
    (include background materials)
  - Miscellaneous election materials, 1974, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Photographs (Box 3)
    The Photographs include pictures of Storms at meetings and photos of prohibition-related memorabilia.